One giant leap into the unknown.
First Man is a history, drama film directed by Damien Chazelle.
A look at the life of the astronaut, Neil Armstrong, and the legendary space mission
that led him to become the first man to walk on the Moon on July 20, 1969.
Neil Armstrong, played by Ryan Gosling.
Janet Shearon, played by Claire Foy.
Ed White, played by Jason Clarke.
Deke Slayton, played by Kyle Chandler.
Buzz Aldrin, played by Corey Stoll.
Elliot See, played by Patrick Fugit.
First Man is a 2018 American biographical drama film directed by Damien
Chazelle from a screenplay by Josh Singer, based on James R.
Hansen's 2005 book First Man: The Life of Neil A.
The film stars Ryan Gosling as Neil Armstrong, alongside Claire Foy, Jason Clarke, Kyle Chandler, Corey Stoll, Christopher Abbott, and Ciarán Hinds, and follows
the years leading up to the Apollo 11 mission to the Moon in 1969, exploring the triumphs, and the cost on Armstrong, his family and his colleagues.
The project was originally announced in 2003, with
Clint Eastwood slated to direct.
After that rendition fell through, Chazelle, Gosling and Singer all signed on by
2015, and principal photography began in Atlanta in November 2017.
First Man had its premiere at the Venice Film Festival on August 29, 2018, and was
released in the United States on October 12, by Universal Pictures.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing $105.7
million worldwide on a $59 million production budget.
However, it received widespread praise, particularly regarding the direction, Gosling
and Foy's performances, musical score, and the Moon landing sequence.
It received numerous accolades, including four nominations at the
91st Academy Awards (winning Best Visual Effects).
The film explores themes of moon, based on novel or book, sacrifice, nasa, wife.
The tone is emotional.